本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
欢迎光临神秘小屋  先生们
Welcome to the Mystery Shack, gentlemen.
你们有什么需要的吗  钥匙圈  雪花水晶球
What can I get you... Key chains, snow globes,
还是这些稀有的美国总统照片
these rare photos of American presidents?
这就是重力泉镇
This is Gravity Falls...
翻滚吧  迪迪
Flip-a-dip-dip!
重力泉有着不为人知的黑暗面
Gravity Falls has this secret dark side...
哇  不会吧
Whoa! Shut up!
一个俄勒冈州的怪诞小镇
A small town in Oregon
在这里  即将进入青春期龙凤胎迪普和梅宝・派恩斯
where preteen twins Dipper and maple pines...
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
时光宝宝  你在这儿干啥呢
Time baby, w-what are you doing here?
不要啊
No!
滚开  你真是可笑
Move out of the way. You're ridiculous.
这些东西他们早知道了  是不是
They already know all of this, don't you?
你们对那些暗号  密码  线索了如指掌
You know about the codes, the cyphers, and the clues.
不过是藏着我个人神秘隐私的箱子而已
It's just my personal box of mysterious secrets.
永别了
Goodbye forever!
好吧  这就有点奇怪了
Well, this is getting weird.
但是你以为重力泉背后的秘密仅此而已吗
But you think that's the mystery behind Gravity Falls?
这个小镇有着你压根无法理解的秘密
This town has secrets you couldn't begin to comprehend.
真是让我开怀大笑
That makes me laugh
也有点让我口水直流  可能需要一块新尿布了
and drool a little bit, and maybe I need a new diaper.
但重点是  重力泉蕴藏的秘密
The point is, there is so much more
比你想象中的还要多
to gravity falls than you ever imagined.
那个  我能不能向您请教
So, uh, would you mind if I ask you
小几百万个有关重力泉的问题
a couple billion questions about Gravity Falls?
嗯
Um...
我是怎么知道的呢
And how do I know?
这个嘛  毕竟本宝宝可是跨次元的最高霸主
Well, because I'm a multidimensional overlord.
我还有来自另一边的资源
But I also have access to the other side.
我把剧集主创  亚历克斯・赫希关在一间屋子里了
I have Alex Hirsch, the creator, trapped in a room,
我会逼他把脑子里的东西全都讲出来
and I will force him to share the inner workings of his mind.
你是来偷我眼睛的吗
Have you come to steal my eyes?!
我都不知道说什么好了  有好多问题想问
I don't know what to say. I have so many questions.
感觉要吐了
I... ohh! I think I'm gonna throw up!
我是不会泄露这些机密的  伙计们
I'm never gonna reveal these secrets, guys.
你不能逼我
You can't make me.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： WaitinZ
翻译： Wizard小希  WaitinZ  GUMP  emerald  Enpistu
■
校订  后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
怪诞小镇  特别节目  解密派恩斯
Gravity Falls: Between the Pines
时光宝宝嘛  如果你面临
Uh, Time Baby, i-if you're ever being...
如果时光宝宝想跟你打一架的话
I-if time baby's ever trying to fight you...
肃静
Silence!
赶紧跑出房间就是了
Just leave the room.
他不知道有物体恒存性
He doesn't have object permanence.
这样他就会以为你已经不在了
H-he'll think you're not there anymore.
废话少说  亚历克斯
Quit stalling, Alex!
这个节目的主角又不是我
This show isn't about me.
快点揭开你的秘密吧
Reveal your secrets!
时光宝宝是一个大傻孩
Time Baby is a big, dumb baby.
才不是呢
I am not.
你能把我怎么样啊  时光宝宝
What are you gonna do, time baby, huh?
难道想干掉我不成
You gonna zap me?
够了
Enough!
我想说  如果你想重温一遍这个剧集的话
I'd say, if you're rewatching the series all over again,
一定要特别注意背景
pay particular attention to the backgrounds.
可能这屋子里也没有什么奇怪的事发生
Maybe nothing creepy going on in this room.
在《吉迪恩崛起》这一集(S01E20)里  我们在闪回中
In "Gideon Rises," we see a flashback
看到了未知作者的一只手在日志上写字
of the hand of the unknown author writing the journals.
这里有一个骷髅头  一个漆面的书桌
We see a skull, we see a polished desk,
还能看到上面有一点彩虹的映像
but we also see a bit of a rainbow reflection.
眼尖的粉丝可能会注意到
A really keen-eyed fan might notice...
在《变身地毯》这一集(S01E16)的密室里
That, inside the secret room in “Carpet Diem,"
有一个三角形的玻璃三棱镜
there is a triangular glass prism
折射出一道彩虹
that's casting a rainbow reflection.
这正是在微妙地暗示
It's a subtle way to let you know
这个房间曾经属于作者
that that room belonged to the author.
我觉得好像还没人发现这一点呢
I don't think anyone's actually ever figured that one out yet.
这个破旧的小屋有着不计其数的诡异秘密
This old shack is full of weird secrets.
迪普是根据我的童年回忆创作出来的
Dipper is based on my memory of how it felt to be a kid.
我滴个天啊
Holy mackerel!
在我像迪普这么大的时候
When I was around Dipper's age,
我会给自己录音  然后再倒着放出来
I would record myself and play it backwards.
我试着学习倒着说话
I tried to learn to speak backwards.
迪迪迪迪普・派恩斯
D-d-d-Dipper Pines.
我就知道  果然还是有思想控制
I knew it! It's mind control, after all!
我那时候没什么朋友
I didn't have a lot of friends.
本宝宝一点也不觉得惊讶
Time Baby is not surprised.
其实时光宝宝没有他自认为的那么全知全能
Time baby doesn't know as much as he thinks he knows.
该知道的我都知道
I know all there is to know!
我上中学的时候
When I was in middle school,
我班上有一个小孩
I was in a class with a kid who had...
这不是他自己的错  他有一些很奇怪的粉刺
No fault of his own... Some really unusual acne.
每天都会变化一点
Every day, it was a little different.
给我看  给我看
Show me! Show me!
所以我就会像记录星座一样
So I would sort of chart the constellations
把图案记在我的速写本上
from my sketchbook,
我记得有一天  他头上出现了一个完整的北斗七星
and I remember one day, he had a perfect big Dipper,
一模一样  就在他的额头上
the exact right dots, on his forehead.
原来你的小名就是这么来的啊
That's how you got your nickname.
我还以为是你父母讨厌你还是怎么的呢
I thought your parents just hated you or something.
快说他的真名是什么
Reveal his first name!
我不能说啊
I can't say it.
以“迪”开头  以“普”结尾
It begins with a "d" and ends with an "ipper."
我叫多普
My name is Dopper.
嗯  罗德里克
And, Roderick...
-呃  其实呢  -说的就是你  亲爱的小孩
- Uh, actually, uh... - You, dear boy.
快说
Confirm!
不要
Uh, no.
现在就说
Now!
我觉得时光宝宝该睡会儿了
I think time baby needs a nap.
你才该睡会儿了呢
Your face needs a nap.
迪普和梅宝的名字之间是有关联的
Dipper and Mabel's first names have a similarity,
但是我是不会告诉你们具体有什么关联的
but I will not tell you what that similarity is.
-神秘双胞胎  -我还以为你不喜欢这样呢
- Mystery twins? - I thought you hated that.
我开始学着接受了
I'm starting to accept it.
呃  好吧  咱们开始讲梅宝的事吧
Ugh, fine. Let's move on to Mabel.
她是一个没啥城府的简单生物
She is a simple creature with nothing to hide.
梅宝
Mabel?
每集她不在镜头前的时候
Every time she's not on camera in an episode,
她都忙着织下周要穿的毛衣呢
she's off knitting the next week's sweaters.
苏斯
Soos!
梅宝的灵感来源于我的双胞胎姐姐
Mabel is inspired by my twin sister,
尤其是她在小学时候的样子
specifically the way she acted in elementary school.
搞定  一百万个啪啪圈
Boom! A million slap bracelets!
我记着六年级的时候吧
And I think sixth grade, it finally happened
我姐姐终于比我高了
where, like, my sister grew taller than me.
她恰好比你高一毫米
She's got exactly one millimeter on you.
第二年  我几乎长了一倍
The next year, I just like doubled in height.
我是老大  我是老大
Alpha twin! Alpha twin!
你要问现在的情况  当然我是老大了
I am the Alpha twin now, if you ask me.
啊  游泳池
Ah, the pool...
魅力夏天中的闪闪绿洲
Sparkling oasis of summer enchantment.
是啊  没什么比和陌生人坐在潮湿的浴缸里更享受了
Yeah, nothing like sitting in a moist tub with strangers.
就好像挤公交  不过是湿的
It's like the bus but wet.
斯坦叔公的原型是我的爷爷斯坦
Grunkle Stan is based on my grandpa Stan.
斯坦当然是个有秘密的人
Stan certainly has secrets.
天啊
Sweet Sally.
说出来
Share them!
看回放你就明白了
Catch you on the rewind.
如果你要把这部片子再看一遍
If you're rewatching the series,
格外注意斯坦谈论家人的方式
watch closely how Stan talks about family...
今天我们要享受真正的家庭乐趣
Today, we're gonna have some real family fun.
现在  谁想戴上眼罩然后跟我上车啊
Now, who wants to put on some blindfolds and get into my car?
耶
Yay!
和他看待家人的方式
Thinks about family...
当你说“闭嘴老家伙”的时候就已经征服我了
Shh! You had me at "shut up, old man."
你就会觉得更有意思了
And it will make a lot more sense.
你会发现一些拼图的碎片可以拼在一起了
You'll notice that some of the puzzle pieces have fit together.
就别操心地下室里的事情了
Don't worry about what's in the basement.
你属于地上  跟我和梅宝在一起
You belong up here with me and Mabel.
是呀
Yeah.
既然我们都知道斯坦叔公有个双胞胎兄弟了
Now that we know Grunkle Stan has a twin brother,
那么你再去看像《猎头者》这一集(S01E03)的时候
when you watch an episode like "Headhunters"...
你想要什么吗
You need anything?
我爱死你了  呆在这儿别动哦
I love this guy. Don't you go nowhere.
你看到当他的蜡像被毁坏
You see how distraught he is...
他那心烦意乱的样子
that a wax double of him gets destroyed,
你可能就会更好地理解他的心理状况了
you might understand the psychology there a little bit better.
不
No-o-o-o!!
蜡像斯坦被  被谋杀了
Wax Stan... He's been m-m-murdered!
有意思  不过我们必须继续往下讲了
Interesting. But we must continue forward.
你不想知道些苏斯的秘密吗
Don't you want to learn some Soos secrets?
苏斯绝对是我最喜欢配音的角色之一
Soos is definitely one of my favorite characters to voice.
今晚我吃掉了一个活生生的人
I ate a man alive tonight.
我们的编剧之一  杰夫
One of our writers, Jeff...
他有时候喜欢说些奇怪的  自造的嘻哈词语
He kind of speaks in weird, made-up hip-hop terms...
苏斯也就开始说这种东西了
And Soos starts saying those kinds of things.
小鲜肉迪迪  你别瞎掺和
You stay out of this, Dippy Fresh!
小鲜肉迪迪又没招惹你  哥们儿
Dippy fresh didn't do anything to you, dawg.
说"啊"  女汉子
Say "ahh," girl dude.
干啥呀  小鬼头
What's up, hambone?
说说这个苏斯是从哪儿来的
Explain where this Soos came from.
苏斯的原型是我的一个大学同学
Soos was inspired by someone I went to college with...
这人名叫赫苏斯・珊布罗
This guy Jesus Chambrot.
我最擅长修理东西  打电玩
I'm great at fixing stuff, playing video games,
留小胡子之类的事情
having a sort of mustache.
他这人挺神秘的
He was kind of a mystery,
不过他总呆在计算机实验室
but he was always in the computer lab,
总是想去帮你
and he always wanted to help you.
末日勤杂工  为您效劳
Handyman of the apocalypse, at your service.
他见了你可能会这样 “嘿  伙计  嘿  伙计”
He would see you and just be like, "hey, dude. Hey, dude.
“打印机需要我帮忙吗” 你如果说 “没事儿  不用”
You need help with the printer?" You'd be like, "no, I'm good."
他就会说 “哦哦  我来帮你把打印机修好”
He'd be like, "oh, oh, I'm gonna help you fix the printer."
我几年前就该想到这一招才对
I should have thought of this years ago.
“诶哟  我把打印机弄坏了”
"Oh, whoops. I broke the printer.
“嘿  你想帮我把我刚弄坏的打印机修好吗”
Hey, you want my help fixing the printer that I just broke?"
救我  我被困在游戏里面了
Help. I'm trapped in the game.
他总是在引起和解决问题
He was always causing and solving problems.
不要弄丢相机
Don't lose your cameras.
-什么  丢掉相机  -别
- Wait. Lose the cameras? - Don't!
伙计  我刚刚扔掉了两部
Dude, I just threw two away.
但他的一言一行都是发自肺腑的
But it always came from the most sincere place.
我的智慧既是祝福也是诅咒
My wisdom is both a blessing and a curse.
我来定规矩  笨蛋  砰
I make the rules, sucka! Boosh!
每个人都把他们认识的最酷的人倒进同一个锅里
Everyone poured the coolest person they knew into a pot,
然后温蒂就诞生了
and Wendy was born.
砰
Boosh.
你把这些东西弄上来的
You put all this stuff up here?
我偶尔抽空溜到上面来玩一下
I may or may not sneak up here during work...
每天都来  无时无刻不在这儿
All the time, every day.
温蒂  你是我见过的最酷的人
Wendy, you're the coolest person I know.
我知道  哥们儿  一会儿再跟我说吧
I know, dude. Tell me about it later.
亚历克斯  那其他角色呢
Alex, what about the other characters?
闪电回合现在开始
Commencing lightning round!
给你六十秒时间
You have 60 seconds.
懒苏珊  她以前两个眼睛都能用
Lazy Susan... she used to have two functioning eyes
直到一次科学实验把一只眼睛给弄坏了
until a science experiment zapped one of them.
啊  我的眼睛
Aah! My eye!
我觉得被我把名字拿来用的那个杜兰德副警长
I don't think the guy I named Deputy Durland after
应该不知道他的名字出现在了一部动画片里吧
knows that there's a cartoon show with his name in it.
希望他永远都不要发现
Hopefully, he never finds out.
如果你发现了的话  向你道歉了  杜兰德
Sorry, Durland, if you ever discover this.
托比・迪特敏德离放弃一切只有几步之遥
Toby Determined is days away from giving up on everything.
托比  你用火鸡浇油管冒充话筒
Your microphone's a turkey baster, Toby.
-确实  -下一个问题
- It certainly is. - Next question.
时光宝宝很容易被钥匙的响声分心
Time Baby is easily distracted by jingling keys...
这是他的小弱点
Little weakness.
哪有
No, I'm not.
普雷斯顿开了一家挡泥板工厂
Preston runs a mud flap factory,
他老婆是85年的挡泥板小姐什么的
and his wife was Miss Mud Flap '85 or whatever,
他就觉得 “她真是美极了”
and he just decided, "oh, she is gorgeous."
今夜  我们将会品尝到最美味的食物
Tonight, we will enjoy only the finest of tastes
享受最高贵的欢乐
and only the snootiest of laughter.
那就是入场券
That's the ticket.
所以  帕西菲卡其实有挡泥板的血统
So, Pacifica is secretly of mud flap blood.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
你差劲透了
You're the worst.
闪电回合完成
Lightning round complete!
吉迪恩  吉迪恩是个坏蛋
Gideon... Gideon's a villain.
母亲
Mother.
我们开了多次头脑风暴讨论他的造型
There was a lot of brainstorming about what he might be like...
尤其是怎么设计他
In particular, what his design was
还有他的头发能引出什么故事
and what was going on with his hair.
有颗该死的考拉QQ糖
One of those infernal gummy koalas
掉到我帅气无边的头发里了
has gotten into my perfect hair!
我们把他设计成大蓬头是想
We gave him big hair with the thought
会不会有个畸形的双胞胎兄弟
that maybe there would be a malformed second twin...
被吉迪恩藏在他的头发里
That Gideon hid with his hair,
就是吉迪恩可能也有一个双胞胎兄弟
that maybe Gideon had a twin, as well.
不 别弄乱我的头发
No! Not the hair!
现在我已经不这样想了
I don't think there is anymore.
现实只是一个幻象  宇宙只是一个全息图像
Reality's an illusion! The universe is a hologram!
买黄金吧  再见
Buy gold! Bye!
他对宇宙是个威胁
He is a danger to our universe.
不能提他的名字  亚历克斯
His name must not be mentioned, Alex.
至于比尔
Bill...
说真的吗
Seriously?
我们创作他
When we came up with him,
完全是出于这样一个主意
was 100% inspired by the idea of,
能不能把一美元背面那个三角形提取出来
what if I took the triangle from the back of the dollar bill,
给他戴顶礼帽  添上笨笨的小胳膊小腿
dressed him up with a top hat and stupid little arms and legs
再用钞票的名称  给他起名比尔
and named him bill after the dollar?
不过你们要称呼我永恒的
But you can call me your new lord and master
新上帝与主人
for all of eternity!
本来他是绿色的
He actually was originally going to be green.
但其中一个设计师说  “不行  这样有点奇怪
One of our artists said, "no, he looks kind of weird.
他看起来像一片树叶”
He looks like a leaf."
所以把他变成黄色
So we made him yellow.
现在他就像一个墨西哥玉米片
And now he looks like a nacho.
有很多这样的地方
There's a lot of things like that,
一个简单的设计实际上有着重要意义
where a simple design actually has a greater significance.
在《梦境冒险》这集(S01E19)
In the episode "dreamscaperers,"
梅宝穿着一件印着落日的毛衣
we see that Mabel is wearing a sunset sweater.
这预示着故事的
That  symbolize the descent
剧情走向将从一片光明渐渐
from our storytelling from a brighter story
向黑暗发展
to a darker story.
我们写了连续的两集
And we set up the two-parter
让吉迪恩接管了小镇
with Gideon's takeover of the town.
一旦我找到最后一本日志  这个小镇就是我的了
Once I find the final journal, I'll rule this town,
你会成为我的王后
with you as my queen!
在《梦境冒险》最初的剧情中
In the original plot for "dreamscaperers,"
我们想着比尔将会进入所有角色的梦中
we imagined that bill was going to enter all the characters' dreams
我们会看到苏斯的内心世界
and we were going to see inside Soos' mind,
也会看到梅宝的内心世界
and we were going to see inside Mabel's mind.
我们把故事简化到斯坦叔公内心世界里
We simplified the story to Stan's mind,
但很多梅宝乐园的主意
but a lot of the ideas for Mabeland
是来自于那个被放弃的方案
came from that alternate idea.
而且  在这一集
Also, within the episode,
我们让比尔首次正式登场
we introduce bill for the first time.
噢  重力泉  回来真好
Oh! Oh, Gravity Falls, it is good to be back.
我猜想你是某种活生生的腹语娃娃
And I take it you're some kind of living ventriloquist dummy.
比尔真的是坏透了
Bill's a real bad guy.
这下可好
Oh, snap.
现在我们回到《女爵的应予》
We now return to "The Duchess Approves,"
由斯特莉・斯坦伯博尔吉斯饰演女爵
starring sturly stembleburgiss as the duchess
格兰普顿・圣・拉普特弗拉伯饰演可笑的舵手
and Grampton St. Rumpterfrabble as irascible coxswain
桑特尔布拉格特・汉普特法宾塞尔
Saunterblugget Hampterfuppinshire.
算了  我要用时光之愿了
Forget it. I'm using a time wish.
我总是在想  如果让我拍一部电视剧
I always thought that, if I was to make a TV show,
要是能在里面藏满疯狂的倒放信息
how great would it be if I made it full of all those
隐蔽的密码和谜题  那该多好啊
crazy backwards messages and secret codes and puzzles
故事板设计师
和编剧
这样如果有像我一样怪异的孩子
that, if there was any kid out there as weird as me,
即将离开新泽西
他们就能找到他们想要的
they would actually find the thing they were looking for.
吞噬时间的邪恶宝宝
粉丝比我聪明一百万倍
Fans are a million times smarter than I am.
这点上我们可是有所领教
I have learned that the hard way.
飞碟是骗局
所以到了第二季  我们决定加大赌注
And so, season 2, we said, yes, let's up the ante.
来弄点更难破解的密码吧
Let's have a code that's harder to crack.
来点隐藏起来的暗号
Let's have a code word that is hidden.
密码
可能又是门卫
Probably just the janitor
亲那个拓荒女人蜡像的声音吧
kissing that wax settler woman again.
诶哟  提醒我删掉那个记忆吧
Woof! Remind me to erase that from my memory.
擦除
如你所愿
So be it.
电容器
我们设下的最隐蔽的密码
Probably the best hidden code we've ever had
变形
大概是《爱神》那集(S02E09)
was in the episode "The Love God."
迪普和梅宝在拥挤的市集上奔跑
Dipper and Mabel are running through a crowded festival,
山
字母一个接一个出现在背景中
and the letters are spaced out in the background.
羊
和
密码那么分散
They're so spread out,
猪
我觉得没有人能找到
I didn't think anyone would ever be able to find them.
果然  节目播出后十分钟
Sure enough, 10 minutes after the episode aired,
就有人找到密码了
somebody had cracked it.
只花了我十五秒钟
It only took me 15 seconds.
此外  还有一个完全是第二季新增的
The other thing we did this season
第一季中没有出现的设计
that we didn't do in season 1 is,
在每集末尾  你会看到一幅
at the very end of the episode, there's a flash,
属于一个更大拼图的单帧画面一闪而过
and you see a single frame of one larger puzzle.
这些画面全都指向了斯坦双胞胎兄弟的出现
And that was all leading up to the big reveal of Stan's twin brother.
这就是我们苦苦等待的反转剧情么
That's the big twist we were waiting for?
都什么骗人的设定
What a rip-off!
我大概一年前就预测到了
I predicted that like a year ago.
这部剧夹带了很多信息量
There's a lot of things in a show
在你无意之间  就这样溜进去了
that you just can't help it, that just slip in.
我都已经走到了这一步  谁又能抓住我呢
I've come this far. Who could possibly catch me now?
在《盲目秘社》这集(S02E07)里
In "Society of the Blind Eye,"
斯坦在调试传送门时
Stan is working on the portal
一部分残骸猛撞到他的手
and a piece of debris bangs his hand.
我们看到他把手包扎好
We see him bandaging his hand up.
然后  在接下来几集中
And then, in the next few episodes,
绷带仍然缠在他手上
he still has that bandage on his hand.
民谣歌曲  是伍德斯迪克音乐节
Folk music! It's the Woodstick Festival!
这样持续了一阵子  直到我们揭开
It took a while before we got to the big answer
传送门的秘密
about what the portal was.
斯坦手上的绷带是个标志  告诉观众  不要担心
Stan's bandage on his hand was a way to show, "don't worry.
故事还在继续  我们并没有忘记
It's still happening. We haven't forgotten.
这些故事是联系在一起的
These stories are connected."
有很多这样的地方
There's a lot of things like that,
第一季第三集
猎头者
如果剧中事物发生了变化  那么在之后的故事情节中
where something will change and stay changed
第二季第六集
恐怖礼品店
也会一直保持这个变化
for the rest of the series.
大大大
Bigger.
太大了
Too big!
肯定是魔力作祟  对不对
This is some kind of magic-y thing, isn't it?
第一季第十八集
历险猪猡纪
苏斯  快看
Soos, look!
是真正的恐龙牙齿
A real dinosaur tooth?
第二季第一集
恐怖卡拉OK
有重大事件就在我们眼皮底下发生
There's something huge going on right under our noses.
第一季第六集
迪普男子汉
美洲狮衬衫  美洲豹衬衫
Puma shirt, panther shirt.
第二季第一集
恐怖卡拉OK
谭布丽刚发给我一条超搞笑的短信
Tambry sends me the craziest text.
每位观众都可以像迪普一样
Each audience member gets to be Dipper
解开这些谜团
and have a mystery to uncover.
在这个小镇  没什么是不可能的
In this town, anything is possible.
在《斯坦的秘密》这一集(S02E11)中
In "not what he seems,"
梅宝的毛衣上有把钥匙
Mabel's wearing a key.
你们抓错人了  斯坦叔公可能偶尔会顺走人家的橘子
Our Grunkle Stan might shoplift the occasional tangerine,
但他绝不是什么超级大坏蛋
but he's not some evil supervillain.
这是因为梅宝自身就是钥匙
This is because Mabel herself
最后是梅宝打开了传送门
is ultimately the key to unlocking the portal.
看着我的眼睛  梅宝
Look into my eyes, Mabel!
你真的觉得我是个坏人吗
You really think I'm a bad guy?
他在撒谎  快关了机器
He's lying! Shut it down now!
梅宝  求你了
Mabel, please!
十  九
10... 9...
"神秘之轮"时间到
It's time for "wheel of secrets"!
诺曼嘴边那一坨红色的东西
That red stuff on Norman's mouth...
是血还是果酱
Is it blood, or is it jam?
其实是果酱
It really is jam.
小矮人们的女王刚刚去世
The gnomes recently had their gnome queen die,
它们在葬礼上都吃了丧友果酱
and as part of her funeral ceremony,
这是它们的一项传统
they were all eating bereavement jam.
这很正常
This is normal.
我们本来想把多头熊叫做熊熊
Originally, the multi-bear was going to be called the bear bear,
而且我们还很想让迪普说这么一句台词
and we specifically wanted a line where Dipper could say,
"熊熊  乖乖"
"there, there, bear bear."
哦  那就是多头熊
Oh, that's a multi-bear.
布伦丁秃头是有原因的
We have a reason that Blendin is bald.
他时空旅行的技术不怎么样
When he time-travels,
所以经常不小心把自己弄着火
oftentimes, he does it poorly and catches on fire.
所以只能拍自己
He has to slap himself.
他就会这么说"噢  熄  熄灭"
It's like, "oh, pat! Pat down!"
他在时空旅行中笨手笨脚的  把自己的头发都烧光了
He's burned off all his hair from botched time traveling.
我不知道这是不是某种悖论
I don't know if it's some kind of paradox,
还是我太累了
or if I'm just really tired.
我们最后给麦戈科特写了一首歌
We ended up writing a song for McGucket
是关于湖怪的
where he sings about the gobblewonker
讲它们是真的  而且会找上你
and how it's real and how it's gonna get you.
然后我们意识到了两件事
And then we learned two things...
一  这首歌太长了
One, the song was too long.
二  麦戈科特唱歌太烂了
Two, McGucket's a terrible singer.
这可能也是我住在垃圾堆的原因
That's probably why I live in the dump!
在《两个斯坦》这一集(S02E12)中
In "a tale of two Stans,"
你会看到斯坦在中学科学展上失败的作品
you see that Stan's science-fair project
就是一个叫作橄榄机器人的橄榄球机器人
that failed in high school was a football robot called footbot.
很显然  这是他长久以来一直追寻的梦想
This is apparently a dream he has had for a very long time,
还是个很傻的梦想
and it's a very dumb dream.
你啥都没赢
You didn't win anything.
这部剧还有个秘密  知道的人不多
One secret about the show that not a lot of people know
剧中很多龙套角色
is that some names of incidental characters
以及无关紧要的小配角  他们的名字
or side characters that don't really matter in the show...
嘿  我是盖比・班森
Hey, I'm Gabe Bensen, y'all.
这是李跟内特
This is Lee and Nate.
很多都是根据我姐姐上小学或者中学时
A number of them are based on boys my sister had a crush on
喜欢的男生起的
in middle school and elementary school.
梅宝  回击得好棒
Awesome comeback, Mabel.
塞勒  别拿我当小朋友
Don't treat me like a child, xyler.
她给我打电话  然后说
She called me up, and she's like,
"你干嘛要起这个名字"
"what is that guy's name doing in there?"
然后我就说"别担心  我不会告诉别人的"
I was like, "don't worry. I won't tell anybody."
呃  所以  千万别告诉别人
Um, so, please don't tell anybody.
姑娘  你让我行为如此疯狂
Girl, you got me actin' so cray cray
疯狂
Cray cray
你说你不会做我的宝贝
You tell me that you won't be my baby
我姐姐爱过不止一个男孩乐队
My sister loved not just one boy band,
也不止两个
not just two boy bands,
而且每个男孩乐队都和其他的差不多
but every boy band that was a rip-off of the other boy band.
-嗨  迪普  -嗨  迪普
- Hey, Dipper. - Hey, Dipper.
嗨  迪普
Hey, Dipper.
她墙上有他们所有人的海报
And she had a poster for all of them on her wall.
哦  那是真的吗  梅宝姑娘
Whoa. Is that true, Mabel dawg?
一个人心里哪有那么大的地方
How is there enough room in your heart
能痴迷这么多男孩乐队啊
to be obsessed with this many boy bands?
我爱你  深度・克里斯
I love you, Deep Chris!
他是对我说的
He was talking to me!
爱丽尔・赫希配音
剧中很多内容都来自我们互相取笑
A lot of the show is us making fun of each other
或是取笑我们的朋友或兄弟姐妹
or our friends or our siblings.
让我看看被嘲弄的对象
Show me the object of ridicule.
梅宝吃笑笑糖的时候
When Mabel does the smile dip
她被糖迷得晕晕乎乎
and she's on this crazy sugar trip...
想尝尝我的糖爪子吗
Would you like to eat my candy paws?
她骑着海豚说
As she's riding this dolphin and says...
前进  鲨鱼怪
Onwards, Aoshima!
现在我去漫展的时候  好多孩子在那里对我喊
Now I go to comic-con, and a hundred kids chant,
“前进  鲨鱼怪” 但他们不知道
"onwards, Aoshima!" To me, having no idea
那只是我们导演的名字  约翰・青岛
that that's just the name of our director, John Aoshima.
你的幽默感真让我着迷
I am charmed by your sense of humor.
美男鱼的配音是马特・查普曼
Mermando is voiced by Matt Chapman,
我们的编剧之一  他在剧中给很多角色配音
one of our writers, who does many voices on the show.
多次乐队的很多成员都是他配的音
He's many of the members of Sev'ral Timez...
但是他把我们关在笼子里
But he keeps us in cages!
那个废物真是太残忍了  姑娘
That junk is straight brutal, girl.
奥地利王子也是他
He is the Austrian prince...
你确实有特殊之处
There's something about you.
让我魂牵梦萦
I can't get you out of my head.
你那么大胆  那么自信
You're so bold and confident.
苏斯的奶奶也是他
And he is abuelita.
我要用吸尘器清理墙壁
I vacuum the walls now.
珊多拉・西梅内斯  我是个真正的记者
Shandra Jimenez, a real reporter.
我可以告诉你关于珊多拉的一件事
One thing I can tell you about Shandra
她的名字来自于我们的一位场景设计师
is that her name is inspired by one of our background artists,
肖恩・西梅内斯
Sean Jimenez.
我是珊多拉・西梅内斯  晚餐我吃了一只老鼠
I'm Shandra Jimenez, and I ate a rat for dinner.
关于鲍尔斯特工  可能有些人还不知道
Something that not everyone might know about Agent Powers
他的配音是尼克・奥弗曼
is that he is voiced by Nick Offerman...
如果你真的有关于这些事件的证据
If very evidence of these claims,
我们应该谈谈
we should talk.
他是位很搞笑的喜剧演员
Who is a hilarious comedian.
我生来就因为一种罕见的
I was born with a rare disorder
生理障碍而无法领会到幽默
that makes me physically incapable of experiencing humor.
我能证实  一点也不好笑
I can confirm... Not funny.
可能有人不知道特瑞格特工
Something people might not know about agent trigger...
他的颧骨和下巴的造型参考了
His sort of cheekbones and chin were kind of modeled after
我们的一位编剧  杰夫・罗
one of our writers, Jeff Rowe,
他是我们编剧室里的头号美男子
who is the most attractive man in our writers' room.
我们活下来了  九死一生
We survived... barely.
我用特瑞格当人肉盾牌
I used trigger as a human shield.
提醒一下  以防你还没注意到
And in case you didn't notice,
他们一直都在监视着双胞胎
they've been watching the twins the whole time.
亚历克斯  羊羔舞是怎么回事呢
What about the lamby dance, Alex?
那是你的事儿  对吧
That was you, wasn't it?
现在不是讨论羊羔舞的时候啦
Now is not the time to talk about the lamby dance.
我们的一位编剧  迈克尔・里安达
One of our writers, Michael Rianda...
他小时候  他姐姐
His sister, when he was a child,
把他打扮成一只小羊羔让他跳舞
dressed him up as a lamb and made him do a dance.
很多人都以为那是我
A lot of people think that was me...
好  谁想要一只小羊羔
Well... who wants a lamby, lamby, lamby?
我要  我要
I do! I do!
可惜并不是
Fortunately, it was not.
别忘了你的宝贝
...Forget about the baby!
其实这一段是来源于他饱受创伤的童年阴影
That specifically comes from his traumatic childhood memory.
说来  似乎所有的编剧
Um, so, it's like all the writers
都有一部分个性特征悄悄地
have a secret sort of personality trait
融入了这部剧集
that sneaks into the show.
给白色大猩猩戴上彩虹假发
Putting a rainbow wig on a big, white gorilla
开车唱着歌
singing the driving song do-do do-do-do
没开车前灯  看不清目的地
headlights are out, can't really see where I'm going do-do-do do-do
这是我的小习惯
That's just something I do.
比如  如果我在找钥匙  就会
Like, if I'm looking for my keys, I'll just be like...
钥匙哪去了
Where are my keys?
脑筋不灵了
I'm losing my mind
到底去哪儿了
where'd they go?
走向我的车
Do-do-do do-do, walking to my car
亚历克斯  时间不多了
Time is running out, Alex.
再跟大家多说点
Tell them more!
美利坚  美利坚
U.S.A.! U.S.A.!
美利坚
U.S.A.!
在编剧室里  时不时会爆发出阵阵口号
Chanting, I think, would happen a lot in the writers' room.
做完  做完
Over with! Over with!
变漂亮  变漂亮
Beautiful! Beautiful!
迈克尔・里安达  如果午饭时间到了
Michael Rianda, if it would be lunchtime,
他就会喊 “午饭时间  午饭时间”
he would do, "lunchtime! Lunchtime!"
舔手肘  舔手肘
Lick it! Lick it! Unh, unh.
我觉得他第一次把喊口号
I think he did the first chant
写进剧集里
that ever appeared in the episode,
是那些中学生一齐高喊“汤普森  汤普森”
which was all the teens going, "Thompson! Thompson!"
这小动作简直太有病了
It's just an obnoxious thing to do,
一旦喊习惯了  根本停不下来
and once you get used to it, you can't stop.
我在剧中客串了很多小配角
There's plenty of little cameos of mine in the show,
我的脸常常出现在角落里
where my face will show up.
人们会认出那是我
People assume that that's, like, me,
觉得“哈哈  逮到你了” 然后小小地骄傲一下
like, "oh, ha ha. Get this," like a little ego boost.
剧组喜欢拿我开玩笑
The crew likes to make fun of me.
每当他们把我的脸塞进画面里
And whenever they put my face in the show,
各种玩笑就被制造出来了
that's their way of doing it.
亲爱的爸爸妈妈  我们在重力泉
Dear mom and dad, we've been in Gravity Falls
已经几个月了  发生了很多事情
for a few months, and so much has happened.
从根本上说  《怪诞小镇》并不仅仅重视解谜和彩蛋
Ultimately, "Gravity Falls" isn't just about codes
这是一部注重塑造角色的剧集
and easter eggs... It's about characters.
你需要一个开着皮卡的可爱助手吗
You need an amiable sidekick with a pickup truck?
你知道我要的
You know I do.
我知道自己的家人是谁了  就是你们啊
I know who my family is now, and it's you dudes.
有人恋爱喽
Somebody's in love!
我这辈子再也没有机会告诉你
I never even got a chance to tell you...
我  好像  爱上你了  温蒂
I'm, like, in love with you, Wendy.
其实我一直都知道
I always kind of knew.
我所做的一切  我所关心的一切
Everything I've worked for, everything I care about...
都是为了这个家
It's all for this family.
总有那么一天  你我会启航
One of these days, you and me are gonna sail away
离开这个落后的小镇
from this dumb town.
夏天结束后  你把房子还给我
When the summer's over, you give me my house back,
名字也还给我
you give me my name back,
然后永远关掉这个破烂神秘小屋
and this mystery shack junk is over forever.
我也从没有意识到  这是我们的最后一个万圣节
I guess I didn't realize it was already our last one.
听着  世界不可能永远定格在这一刻
Look, things aren't gonna stay frozen this way.
这是成长的一部分
It's part of growing up.
势不可挡
Things change.
寒来暑往
Summer ends.
这个暑假  我见识到了许多神奇的事
This summer, I've seen some amazing things,
但最出色的还是你们姐弟俩
but nothing as amazing as you and your sister.
不
No-o-o-o-o!
太好啦
Yes!
哦不  我该做什么
Oh, no! What do I do?!
斯坦利  斯坦利
Stanley! Stanley!
做点什么
Do something!
斯坦利
Stanley!!
斯坦福
Stanford!
这本日志告诉我在重力泉
This journal told me there was no one
不能相信任何人
in Gravity Falls I could trust.
但是当你跟某人肩并肩
But when you battle a hundred gnomes
与上百个小矮人作战的时候
side by side with someone,
你意识到他们或许会永远支持你
you realize that they've probably always got your back.
我说  谁会为了一个傻兄弟
I mean, who would sacrifice
就牺牲自己辛苦得到的一切呢
everything they've worked for just for their dumb sibling?
兄弟  别担心  无论去哪儿  我们都会在一起
Don't worry, bro. Wherever we go, we go together.
我不知道未来会发生什么
I don't know what's gonna happen in the future,
但无论发生什么  你都不要害怕
but whatever it is, you don't have to fear
因为我们会一起面对
because we'll do it together.
没人能救得了这个小镇的人们了吗
Is there no one who will save the people of this town?
我们一起打败比尔  一起长大吧
Let's beat bill and grow up together.
好了  大家都准备好了吗
All right, guys, are you ready for this?!
对不起了  梅宝乐园
Sorry, Mabeland.
是时候戳破你这个大泡泡了
It's time to burst your bubble!
大伙  干掉他们
Let's get 'em, dudes.
最大的谜底还在等待揭晓
And the biggest secrets are yet to be revealed.
拿下  拿下
Get it. Get it.
拿下
Get iiiit.
拿下  拿下
Get it. Get it.
拿下
Get 'em.
Got it.
你们几个不会真要把这玩意儿在电视上播出吧
You guys aren't actually gonna put this on TV, are you?
好吧  我  我该走了
All right, I'm... I'm done here.